# Will O'Neill

Writer, Narrative Designer and Game Developer

706-410 Queens Quay W. Toronto, ON M5V 3T1 **(647) 206-7504** 

will.oneill@outlook.com
https://willoneill.carrd.co/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **WZO Games Inc.**, Toronto — Founder

2013 - PRESENT

Creator of the critically acclaimed narrative-focused games Actual Sunlight, Little Red Lie and F2P mobile game Guildmaster Story.

## Pillow Castle Games, Seattle — Writer

2019 - PRESENT

Writing and narrative development on SUPERLIMINAL.

## **Power Struggle Games**, Lyon — Writer & Narrative Designer

2019 - PRESENT

Writing and narrative development on The Invisible Hand.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **University of Toronto**, Toronto — Bachelor of Arts

2000 - 2004

**English and Philosophy** 

## **Centennial College**, Toronto — *Postgraduate Certificate*

2004 - 2005

Public Relations & Corporate Communications

#### **TRAINING**

## **Unreal Engine** — *Udemy*

Completed Ben Tristem course on Blueprint development and Rick Davidson course on cinematic development

# **Unity** — Certified Developer

Passed exam on first attempt, prepped via Ben Tristem Udemy course.

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

11,000+ Reviews on Steam

Eight games shipped on all current platforms - Steam, PS4, PS Vita, Xbox, iOS and Android - including three self-published on PC and console

8+ years experience in games writing, with 10+ in corporate communications and copywriting

#### **SKILLS**

Engines: Unity, RPG Maker, Adventure Game Studio (AGS), Ren'py

Narrative Tools: Articy Draft, Arcweave, Adventure Creator, Fungus

Voiceover Direction: Remote and in-studio, extensive across game and corporate clients

Production: Affinity Photo /
Designer, Adobe Photoshop /
Illustrator, Logic Pro,
Audacity, Shotcut, Final Cut
Pro

Publishing: Managed Steam and console submissions -TRC process, ratings (IARC, ESRB, PEGI), store

submissions, etc.